<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>MonoGame.Extended Blog</title>
        <link>https://monogameextended.net/blog/</link>
        <description>MonoGame.Extended Blog</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Update Status 2024-06-12]]></title>
            <link>https://monogameextended.net/blog/update-2024-06-12/</link>
            <guid>https://monogameextended.net/blog/update-2024-06-12/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Hi everyone,]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hi everyone,</p>
<p>I wanted to take a moment and give a report on some of the progress made so far in getting version 4.0 officially released.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="current-status">Current Status<a class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Current Status" title="Direct link to Current Status" href="https://monogameextended.net/blog/update-2024-06-12/#current-status">​</a></h2>
<p>If you take a look at the <a href="https://github.com/craftworkgames/MonoGame.Extended/milestone/8" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">v4.0.0 Milestone</a> page, you can see we are now at 55% completed</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="4.0.0 Milestone 55% Completed" src="https://monogameextended.net/assets/images/milestone-55-7f47251367acf0c27e1dff1848c3ae5d.png" width="897" height="383" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>If you'd like to checkout the list of issues that have been worked through so far, you can view them <a href="https://github.com/craftworkgames/MonoGame.Extended/issues?q=is%3Aissue%20is%3Aclosed%20project%3Acraftworkgames%2F6" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">here</a>.</p>
<p>A lot of the remaining issues here could be closed with better documentation, which is going to come in the last leg of this sprint. However, with the current pace, the current deadline of end of June is looking good.  If you'd like to get involved in helping resolve the backlog of issues, please do. Be sure to checkout the <a href="https://github.com/craftworkgames/MonoGame.Extended/blob/develop/CONTRIBUTING.md" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Contributing Guidelines</a> and fee free to contact me on discord with any questions.</p>
<p>And with that status report out of the way, I wanted to touch on some other subjects</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="repository-changes">Repository Changes<a class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Repository Changes" title="Direct link to Repository Changes" href="https://monogameextended.net/blog/update-2024-06-12/#repository-changes">​</a></h2>
<p><strong>MonoGame.Extended</strong> is an extension of <strong>MonoGame</strong>.  With this thought in mind, I have begun to restructure the project some, as many may have already noticed.  The reason behind this is that I feel things in Monogame.Extended should be placed in logical places that match types they are working with in MonoGame.  This keeps the source code structure similar to MonoGame which is beneficial for users working from source between both projects.</p>
<p>What do I mean by this though?  Well, one example is the <code>RectangleExtensions</code>.  Previously it was placed in <code>MonoGame.Extended.Math</code>  However <code>Rectangle</code> in MonoGame exits in the root namespace, not in a <code>Math</code> namespace.  So <code>RectangleExtensions</code> will be moved to the project root to match the similar structure.  Some other changes, like <code>TextureRegion2D</code> is currently located in the <code>MonoGame.Extended.TextureAtlases</code> directory/namespace. At first, this seems like a logical fit, but a <code>TextureRegion2D</code> is a region of a <code>Texture2D</code>.  Atlases just use them, you don't have to have an atlas to use a <code>TextureRegion2D</code>.  So because they are more locally related to the <code>Texture2D</code> in MonoGame, they will be moved to a similar directory/namespace (<code>MonoGame.Extended.Graphic</code>).</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="in-conclusion">In Conclusion<a class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to In Conclusion" title="Direct link to In Conclusion" href="https://monogameextended.net/blog/update-2024-06-12/#in-conclusion">​</a></h2>
<p>I know no one like change, and changes like this may seem superfluous, but I do believe it will be a better user experience moving forward with 4.0.  However, I do value community feedback, so please give me your thoughts and feedback on this in the comment section at the end of this document.  We're halfway there to the 4.0.0 release.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[MonoGame.Extended Is Back]]></title>
            <link>https://monogameextended.net/blog/mongame-extended-is-back/</link>
            <guid>https://monogameextended.net/blog/mongame-extended-is-back/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[It has been far too long since an official release was made of MonoGame.Extended.  Issues have piled up on GitHub, and everyone just wants to import Tiled maps.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It has been far too long since an official release was made of MonoGame.Extended.  Issues have piled up on GitHub, and everyone just wants to import Tiled maps.</p>
<p>So let's change that!</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="hello-monogame-community">Hello MonoGame Community<a class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Hello MonoGame Community" title="Direct link to Hello MonoGame Community" href="https://monogameextended.net/blog/mongame-extended-is-back/#hello-monogame-community">​</a></h2>
<p>Before moving further, I want to take a moment and introduce myself.  Who is this person saying that MonoGame.Extended is back.  Well, my name is Chris Whitley, also known as Aristurtle in the MonoGame Community.  I have been working with MonoGame for several years and maintain other open source libraries for MonoGame.  I am also a contributor to the main MonoGame repository as well.</p>
<p>Outside of working with MonoGame and doing game development, I am a full stack dotnet web developer.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="change-of-responsibility">Change of Responsibility<a class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Change of Responsibility" title="Direct link to Change of Responsibility" href="https://monogameextended.net/blog/mongame-extended-is-back/#change-of-responsibility">​</a></h2>
<p>The previous maintainer, Lucas Girouard-Stranks <a href="https://github.com/lithiumtoast" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@lithiumtoast</a>, has stepped down due to lack of time and interest in maintaining MonoGame.Extended. Moving forward, I will be taking over the <a href="https://github.com/craftworkgames" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">craftworkgames</a> organization on GitHub.  This includes maintaining MonoGame.Extended.</p>
<p>If you have any questions or concerns about this, please contact me on the <a href="https://discord.gg/FvZ8Z7EzPJ" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">MonoGame.Extended Discord Server</a></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="roadmap">Roadmap<a class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Roadmap" title="Direct link to Roadmap" href="https://monogameextended.net/blog/mongame-extended-is-back/#roadmap">​</a></h2>
<p>Coming into MonoGame.Extended as a maintainer, the first priority is getting outstanding issues closed and a new release pushed.  This means my current attention will be focused solely on that goal for now.  New features that have been requested will be pushed back in favor of prioritizing outstanding issues.</p>
<p>I currently have a goal of resolving outstanding issue by the end of June 2024. You can follow the progress of this on the <a href="https://github.com/craftworkgames/MonoGame.Extended/milestone/8" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">v4.0.0 Milestone</a> page.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="acknowledgements">Acknowledgements<a class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Acknowledgements" title="Direct link to Acknowledgements" href="https://monogameextended.net/blog/mongame-extended-is-back/#acknowledgements">​</a></h2>
<p>MonoGame.Extended would not exist were it not for the original maintainer Dylan Wilson <a href="https://github.com/dylanwilson80" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@dylanwilson80</a>, Lucas Girouard-Stranks <a href="https://github.com/lithiumtoast" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@lithiumtoast</a> taking over, and the work done by countless community members over time.  Thank you everyone for all that you have done for this project in the past, and I am honored to be the person leading this into the future.  I look forward to working with you all to continue shaping this into the best extension library for MonoGame.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>